DHARSHAN B D

+91 812 374 2430 ♦ dharshandj@gmail.com ♦ github ♦ linkedIn

OBJECTIVE

Software developer, FOSS enthusiast with 4+ years of experience in developing applications using ruby and ruby on rails technologies, with good understanding of object oriented programming knowledge. Co-Founded twobicle, a location based social networking app.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science Engineering

August 2010 - May 2013

Government Engineering College, Hassan. Visvesvaraya Technological University, 65%

Diploma in Computer Science Engineering

August 2007 - June 2010

Government CPC Polytechnic, Mysore.

DTE, 71%

SSLC, Class X

March 2004 - March 2005

Government High School, Rayarakoppalu, 81.92%

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Programming Languages Ruby, Basics of Python

Operating Systems GNU/Linux based distributions VCS Git, AWS code commit, bitbucket

Database PostgreSQL, PostGIS

Interests Ruby On Rails, ML, Mobile Apps

EXPERIENCE

Twobicle is an android-based application for social discovering, exploring and connecting with people available in your location. Twobicle uses your phone's location to let you explore people around you. You can login with social accounts and connect with these people, invite and message them, exchange information and build a useful localized network using Twobicle.

Co-Founder
February 2018 - present

Bengaluru

- · Contribution
 - Complete backend infrastructure for twobicle.
 - Single handedly designed and developed API only rails infrastructure for twobicle.
 - Responsible for setting up of server infrastructure for towbicle.

Latlong is a company that works on GIS and spatial data related technologies, which helps retail industries to connect with customers by providing multiple services such as Online store Locator(OSL), SMS Store Locator, Route Guide (RG) based on the strong proprietary localised map/GIS data. I worked most on backend services (design and developing RESTfull APIs) for latlong applications and improving the performance and efficiency of latlong applications.

Senior Software Engineer

Latlong Bengaluru

April 2016 - February 2018

· Some of my notable contributions

- maps.latlong.in: Project to showcase latlong's enriched map data and geospatial capabilities.
 - On top of latlong's core routing engine, I implemented different types of driving direction APIs. Which included in requesting direction from place to place, geo point to geo point and vice versa.
 - On top of latong's search engine, I implemented different types of search APIs (geocode) which included searching for different geographical entities within and around a place or a point.
- Location Specifier (Modern Address System)
 - To replace less understandable postal address, LS generates easily understandable information about any given location(geo poit/place) based on latlong's map data. Which includes information about nearest popular places around given location and distance from them.
- Routing API using pgRouting
 - Preparing latlong's geo data suitable for pgRouting and exposing routing geo data over REST API.
- Implemented a built-in monitor and alert feature.
 - A notification system which notifies failures in request processing, with complete request details and error message across multiple channels (mail, sms, slack).
- Latlong Availability Improvement To reduce the load on one server and to improve database availability, I have done the following improvements:
 - High available postgreSQL database cluster setup.
 - Load balancing between database servers in cluster using pgpool II.
- Location based Autocomplete API.
 - Autocomplete suggestoins for area and place based on users location.
 - Implemented full text search engine based on postgreSQLs unique full text search feature.
- Introduced and Implemented standard way of writing ruby code using code analyzers for bug free, optimized and efficient code to improve performance of applications.
- Introduced Agile(Scrum) model to streamline development, improving the efficiency of the development team. Lead the scrum model as scrum master from the beginning.

Software Engineer

Latlong Bengaluru

Feb 2014 - April 2016

- · Projects that I have worked/contributed
 - Upgrading API project from rails version 3.2 to 4.2
 - Worked on changing rails code from version 3.2 to rails version 4.2
 - Internal android applications.
 - An android application to capture different geographical data from users.
 - Online store locator for mobile phone. Worked on creating an android app to mimic the OSL for customers.

Awards/Recognitions

· Speaker at pgconf 2018

pgconf.in latlong.in

· 3 times best employee of the month

PERSONAL PROJECTS [ON GOING]

Alorm: Location based Alarm. A useful app for travellers. Notifies the user when user approach pre-mentioned location/place. Works both in online and offline mode(User need to download offline map data of whole travel plan).

ReadoMeter: ReadoMeter is a ruby gem which calculates estimated amount of time required to read a document and also estimates the user's reading speed.

Porterz: Location based on time delivery service providing platform for small scale industries.

INVOLVMENTS

- Volunteer and organiser for FSMK (Free Software Movement Karnataka) activities.
 - FSMK is a registered not-for-profit organization whose primary objective is to spread and create awareness about free software technologies (FOSS) amongst different sections of the society, driven by volunteers from various backgrounds like software professionals, government officials, academicians and students.
 - The Students Chapter(GLUG- GNU/Linux User's Group) of FSMK works actively with college students and encourages them not only to use free software but also contribute to the development of various free software. Also conducts various technical sessions regularly throughout the academic session.
- Hassan district regional representative for FSMK.
- Active member of BRUG (Bangalore Ruby Users Group).
- Open Source contributer (OSM,Localization).

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Name Dharshan B D
Date of Birth 04th January 1990
Languages Known Kannada, English, Hindi

Marital Status Single

Permanent Address s/o Dharmappa BK, Bharathuru 573129 (Po. Vi.)

Alur (Tq), Hassan (Dist.)

Current Address 1220, 2rd floor, 5th Cross

27th Main, Near RV Dental College approx 300 mtr from RV Dental College 1st Phase JP Nagar, Bangalore 560078